A Guide to the Social Science Research Council records, Soviet Studies, Record Group 3, Series 6 FA1486
Rockefeller Archive Center
- JCSSS (Joint Committee on the Soviet Union and Its Successor States) and Eurasian Program, 1972, 1980-1996; 4
  - JCSSS - Workshop on Imperial Russian History (2) - Notes on Workshop 2 (Susan Bronson), 1994 September 22-25 (Box 117, Folder 1876)
  - JCSS - Conferences on Russian and Soviet Studies, Princeton (1 - 2), 1972, 1980 (Box 117, Folder 1877-1878)
    Two conferences organized by George Kennan at the Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton, 1972 May 12-13, and 1980 August 27-28.
  - JCSSS - Wingspread Conference on the Future of Research on the Former Soviet Union - Schedules and Report, 1992-1994 (Box 117, Folder 1879)
    Draft schedule for 1992 July 16-19 and 1993 June 24-26 conference at Wingspread Conference Center. Report on 1993 conference and follow-up assessment.
  - JCSSS - Wingspread Conference on the Future of Research on the Former Soviet Union - Papers (1 of 2), 1993 June 24-26 (Box 117, Folder 1880)
  - JCSSS - Wingspread Conference on the Future of Research on the Former Soviet Union - Papers (2 of 2), 1993 June 24-26 (Box 118, Folder 1881)
  - JCSSS - BIRD - Guide to Scholarly Resources on Eastern Europe in the New York Metropolitan Area, 1989, 1993-1994 (Box 118, Folder 1886)
  - JCSS - Selection Panel Minutes, 1989-1991 (Box 122, Folder 1956)
    Title VIII Postdoctoral Fellowships, 1989; Title VIII Pre- and Postdoctoral Fellowships and Language Institutes Competition, 1990; Title VIII Pre- and Postdoctoral Fellowships, 1991.
  - JCSSS - Selection Panel Minutes, 1992 (Box 122, Folder 1957)
    First Year Fellowships in Underrepresented Fields; Title VIII Predoctoral Fellowships; Title VIII Postdoctoral Fellowships; Library Backlog Grants Selection; Language Institutes Competition.
  - JCSSS - Selection Panels - Members, 1994 (Box 122, Folder 1958)
    Panels for First Year Felllowships in Underrepresented Fields, Predoctoral Fellowships, and Postdoctoral Fellowships, 1994.
  - JCSSS - Selection Panels - Predoctoral Fellowships, 1995 (Box 122, Folder 1959)
    Graduate Training and Dissertation fellowships.
  - JCSSS - Selection Panels - Predoctoral Fellowships, 1995 (Box 122, Folder 1959 A)
  - JCSSS - Selection Panels - Postdoctoral Fellowships, 1995 (Box 122, Folder 1960)
  - JCSSS - Selection Panels - Postdoctoral Fellowships, 1995 (Box 122, Folder 1960 A)
  - JCSSS - Postdoctoral Application Statistics (for ACLS), 1995 (Box 122, Folder 1961)
  - JCSSS - Chronological Files, 1995 January-February (Box 122, Folder 1964)
    Mainly form letters concerning meeting announcements and participant selection.
  - JCSSS - Chronological Files, 1995 March-December (Box 123, Folder 1965-1967)
  - JCSSS - Membership (Vitae), 1993-1994 (Box 123, Folder 1968)
  - Proposed Soviet Bloc Research and Training Fund, circa 1983 (Box 123, Folder 1969)
    Proposal to create an endowment fund to support a national program of research and training in Soviet and East European studies, through the National Council for Soviet and East European Research (NCSEER), the International Research and Exchanges Board (IREX), and the Woodrow Wilson International Center.
  - Title VIII - Hearings and Legislation, 1982-1983 (Box 123, Folder 1970)
    Subcommittee on European Affairs, Senate Committee on Foreign Relations, 1982 September 22; Conference Committee, 1983 November 17; Office of Management and Budget, Circular A-122.
  - Title VIII - JCSS Grant Agreement and Amendment, 1985 (Box 123, Folder 1971)
    For research and training grant to JCSS (no. 1006-555008), January-September 1985.
  - Title VIII - Consortium Applications (for 1986), 1985 October, 1986 (Box 123, Folder 1972-1974)
    JCSS application in support of fellowship, research, and language-training programs. Consortium supplement to be included with the separate applications of the five member organizations: IREX, Joint Committee on Eastern Europe (JCEE), JCSS, National Council for Soviet and East European Research (NCSEER), and the Kennan Center of the Woodrow Wilson International Center.
  - Title VIII - Consortium Correspondence and Memos, 1986-1988 (Box 123, Folder 1975)
    Includes planning for a proposed "Princeton II" conference in 1986 and for a National Foundation for International Studies; 1988 strategy meeting for support of Title VIII program.
  - Title VIII - Consortium Meetings, 1988-1989 (Box 124, Folder 1976)
  - Title VIII - Workshop on New Directions in Russian, Eurasian, and East European Studies, 1992 October 13-14 (Box 124, Folder 1977)
    Sponsored by the Offfice of Research, Bureau of Intelligence and Research, U.S. Department of State, Washington, DC.
  - Title VIII - Language Training, 1992-1993 (Box 124, Folder 1978)
    Includes Title VIII Advisory Committee report on "U.S. Competency in the Languages of Eastern Europe and Eurasia," 1992.
  - Title VIII - JCSSS Award (FY 1993), 1992-1993 (Box 124, Folder 1979)
  - Title VIII - Funding Issues (FY 1994), 1993 (Box 124, Folder 1980)
    Includes Title VIII Advisory Committee meeting, 1993 December 3.
  - Title VIII - JCSSS Funding (FY 1994) (Box 124, Folder 1981)
  - Title VIII - Congressional Lobbying and Support, 1995 (Box 124, Folder 1982)
  - Joint Advisory Committee on International Programs (JACIP) (ACLS and SSRC) - Soviet Studies Review Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 124, Folder 1983)
    Includes "Beyond Soviet Studies" report, November 1991.
  - The August Revolution and Soviet Studies, 1991 (Box 124, Folder 1984)
    Article by Robert Huber and Susan Bronson for the SSRC newsletter, Items, 45, no. 4 (December 1991).
  - JCSS - Toronto Initiative, 1991 (Box 124, Folder 1985)
    Statement on Ethics and Research in the Soviet Union. Document grew out of a roundtable discussion at the Fourth Annual Domestic Politics Workshop, Toronto, 1991.
  - JCSSS - Meeting Notes, 1994 Fall (Box 124, Folder 1986)
    Unidentified manuscript meeting notes (possibly by Susan Bronson?). Discussion of projects and program directions.
  - JCSS - Fellows Tracking Project, early 1990s (Box 124, Folder 1987)
  - JCSSS - Draft Proposal for Project to Strengthen Social Sciences in Russia, mid-1990s (Box 124, Folder 1988)
  - JCSSS - Foundation Support for Soviet Studies and International Programs - General, 1992-1995 (Box 124, Folder 1989)
  - JCSSS - Post-Soviet Cultural Studies Network, 1994-1995 (Box 124, Folder 1990)
    Also referred to as Post-Soviet Anthropology Group
  - JCSSS - Program Budgeting and Finance, 1994-1996 (Box 124, Folder 1991)
  - JCSSS - Report on Activities for Ford Foundation Annual Report, 1995 (Box 124, Folder 1992)
  - National Academy of Sciences - National Research Council Committee on Revitalizing Social Science in the Former Soviet Union, 1993 (Box 124, Folder 1993)
    Stan Heginbotham memos and Moscow Trip Report, January 27-31, 1993.
  - Eurasia Foundation Proposal, 1993 April (Box 124, Folder 1994)
    Proposal from the SSRC and IREX for funding for a program to develop economic capacity in the newly independent states (NIS) of the former Soviet Union.
  - Eurasia Foundation Proposal - In Country Workshops, 1993 (Box 124, Folder 1995)
  - JCSSS - BIRD (Bibliography, Information Retrieval, and Documentation) - Getty Foundation, 1993-1994 (Box 125, Folder 1996)
    Getty support for St. Petersburg International Center for Conservation; BIRD programs; and PUBWATCH.
  - PUBWATCH, 1992-1995 (Box 125, Folder 1997-1999)
    Organization promoting Western assistance to the book sector in Eastern Europe and the former Soviet Union.
  - IREX / ACA Seminar on International Academic Cooperation with Central and Eastern Europe and Eurasia, 1994 October 13-15 (Box 125, Folder 2000)
    Academic Cooperation Association (Brussels). Seminar in Helsinki.
  - International Research and Exchanges Board (IREX), 1990-1995 (Box 125, Folder 2001-2002)
    Correspondence, memos, and board materials.
  - Dupree Prize for Research on Central Asia, 1993-1994 (Box 125, Folder 2003)
    Prize established in honor of Louis Dupree. First award in 1994.
  - USIA - Social Sciences Training Program for Scholars from the Newly Independent States (NIS), 1993-1994 (Box 125, Folder 2004)
    USIA program to fund university partnerships and training for scholars from the Newly Independent States (NIS). Application form and correspondence. Basis for SSRC and IREX Social Sciences Curriculum Fellowships.
  - JCSSS - IREX Social Science Curriculum Fellowships - General, 1994-1995 (Box 125, Folder 2005)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Faroukshin, Midkhat K., 1995 (Box 125, Folder 2006)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Ilyin, Mikhail V., 1995 (Box 125, Folder 2007)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Ivanov, Vladimir I., 1995 (Box 125, Folder 2008)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Ivanovski, Zbignev V., 1995 (Box 125, Folder 2009)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Kudriashova, Elena V.., 1995 (Box 125, Folder 2010)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Litvinenko, Olga V., 1995 (Box 125, Folder 2011)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Orlova, Anna O., 1995 (Box 126, Folder 2012)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Shumeiko, Alexander A., 1995 (Box 126, Folder 2013)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Sizov, Sergey K., 1995 (Box 126, Folder 2014)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Zuckerman, Galina A., 1995 (Box 126, Folder 2015)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Volkov, Roman F. (Alternate 1), 1995 (Box 126, Folder 2016)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Mintz, Svetlana S. (Alternate 2), 1995 (Box 126, Folder 2017)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Kurashov, Vladimir I. (Alternate 3), 1995 (Box 126, Folder 2018)
  - Social Science Curriculum Fellowships (IREX) - Piskoppel, Anatolyi A. (Alternate 4), 1995 (Box 126, Folder 2019)
  - IREX Social Science Curriculum Fellowships - Applicant Data and Selection Panel, 1995 (Box 126, Folder 2020)
  - IREX Social Science Curriculum Fellowships - Applicant Data and Selection Panel, 1995 (Box 126, Folder 2020 A)
  - IREX Social Science Curriculum Fellowships - Reviewer Comments, 1995 (Box 126, Folder 2021-2022)
  - JCSSS - Building Foreign Policy Institutions Conference - Proposal and Preliminary Work, 1993 (Box 126, Folder 2023)
    Building Foreign Policy Institutions in the Non-Russian Successor States, Kiev, 1995 January 12-15.
  - JCSSS - Building Foreign Policy Institutions Conference - Schedule and Participant List, 1995 January 12-15 (Box 126, Folder 2024)
  - JCSSS - Building Foreign Policy Institutions Conference - Invitations, 1995 January 12-15 (Box 126, Folder 2025)
  - JCSSS - Building Foreign Policy Institutions Conference - U.S. Participant List, 1995 January 12-15 (Box 126, Folder 2026)
  - JCSSS - Building Foreign Policy Institutions Conference - Participants from the Former Soviet Union, 1995 January 12-15 (Box 126, Folder 2027)
  - JCSSS - Building Foreign Policy Institutions Conference - Planning and Logistics, 1995 January 12-15 (Box 126, Folder 2028)
  - JCSSS - Building Foreign Policy Institutions Conference - IIGRS Invitations to Participants, 1995 January 12-15 (Box 127, Folder 2029)
    Invitations from the International Institute on Global and Regional Security (Kiev).
  - JCSSS - Building Foreign Policy Institutions Conference - Grant Accounting and Budget, 1995 January 12-15 (Box 127, Folder 2030)
  - IIGRS (International Institute on Global and Regional Security) Publications, 1994 (Box 127, Folder 2031)
    Reports from Conference on Non-Nuclear Future Way of Ukraine, 1994 April 7-8; and IIRGS publication, The World of Security, II-III (conferences in April and October 1994, partly on topic of territorial and interethnic conflicts). Papers in Russian, with a few contributions in English.
  - Working Group on Central and Inner Asia - Planning, 1990-1992 (Box 127, Folder 2032)
    Planning meeting, 1991 April 29, for a proposed cross-committee working group on Central and Inner Asia. File contains correspondence and draft proposals for a program of comparative study of States, Population, and Social Institutions in Central Asia.
  - Working Group on Central and Inner Asia - Rationale, 1991-1992 (Box 127, Folder 2033)
  - Working Group on Central and Inner Asia - Background Materials, 1986-1991 (Box 127, Folder 2034-2035)
    Newsletter of the Association for Central Asian Studies, 1990; Proceedings of the Workshop on Turkic Societies of the Soviet Union and the Middle East, University of Texas at Austin, 1987; Donald R. Kelley, research proposal for the Workshop on Central Asia in Transition, ca. 1991; course offerings and bibliographic materials, 1986-1991.
  - JCSSS - Initiative on Population, Health, and Ethnography in Central Asia - Proposals, 1993 (Box 127, Folder 2036)
    Proposal to Committee on Problems and Policy for a series of three international workshops.
  - Conference on Population, Family, and Gender in Muslim Central Asia - Schedule and Participant List, 1995 May 31 - June 4 (Box 127, Folder 2037)
    Conference on Population, Family, and Gender in Muslim Central Asia and the Middle East, Istanbul, Turkey. Conference sponsored by the JCSSS and ACLS, the Middle East Research Awards Program of the Population Council, and Bogazici University.
  - Conference on Population, Family, and Gender in Muslim Central Asia - Invitations and Planning, 1995 May 31 - June 4 (Box 127, Folder 2038)
    Correspondence concerning Central Asia participants, 1994; includes CVs and paper abstracts. Includes materials in English and in Russian.
  - Conference on Population, Family, and Gender in Muslim Central Asia - Invitations, 1995 May 31 - June 4 (Box 127, Folder 2039)
  - Conference on Population, Family, and Gender in Muslim Central Asia - Correspondence with Organizers, 1995 May 31 - June 4 (Box 127, Folder 2040)
  - Conference on Population, Family, and Gender in Muslim Central Asia - Correspondence with Participants, 1995 May 31 - June 4 (Box 128, Folder 2041)
  - Conference on Population, Family, and Gender in Muslim Central Asia - Funding, 1992-1994 (Box 128, Folder 2042)
  - Conference on Population, Family, and Gender in Muslim Central Asia - Planning, Expenses, and Local Arrangements, 1993-1994 (Box 128, Folder 2043)
  - Conference on Population, Family, and Gender in Muslim Central Asia - Travel and Expenses, 1995 May 31 - June 4 (Box 128, Folder 2044)
  - Conference on Population, Family, and Gender in Muslim Central Asia - Papers, 1995 May 31 - June 4 (Box 128, Folder 2045-2048)
  - Conference on Population, Family, and Gender in Muslim Central Asia - Papers in Russian or Other Languages, 1995 May 31 - June 4 (Box 128, Folder 2049)
  - JCSS - Title VIII Pre- and Postdoctoral Fellowships - Summary Information, 1985-1987 (Box 129, Folder 2050)
  - JCSS - Title VIII Pre- and Postdoctoral Fellowships Selection Panel, 1986 (Box 129, Folder 2051)
    Includes Applicant Information sheets.
  - JCSS - Title VIII Pre- and Postdoctoral Fellowships Selection Panels, 1987 (Box 129, Folder 2052)
  - JCSS - Title VIII Pre- and Postdoctoral Fellowships Selection Panels, 1987 (Box 129, Folder 2052 A)
  - JCSS - Title VIII Predoctoral Fellowships Selection Panel (Applicant Information Sheets), 1987 (Box 129, Folder 2053)
  - JCSS - Title VIII Predoctoral Fellowships Selection Panel, 1988 (Box 129, Folder 2054)
  - JCSSS - Dissertations, 1989-1996 (Box 129, Folder 2055)
    Dissertations submitted by JCSSS fellows. File contains copy of title-page record only. Dissertation volumes have not been retained.
  - JCSS - Recruitment Program in Russian and Soviet Studies, 1984-1986 (Box 129, Folder 2056)
    Title VIII-sponsored pilot program to recruit students for graduate training in Soviet Studies.
  - Colloquium on the Development of the Revolutionary Situation in Imperial Russia (Leningrad, 1990), 1989 (Box 132, Folder 2082)
    Solicitation for funding from the JCSS for proposed colloquium, May-June 1990.
  - JCSSS - Workshop on the Economics of Transition to Market Systems - Papers, 1995 July 9-21 (Box 133, Folder 2084-2085)
  - Dissertation Fellowships Applicant - Harvey, Brian, 1991-1994 (Box 133, Folder 2086)
    Restricted - Personnel-Type Records - Open in 2035.
  - Dissertation Fellowships Applicant - Krancberg, Sigmund, 1990-1992 (Box 133, Folder 2087)
  - Fertility Decline and Recent Changes in Russia (Paper), circa 1995 (Box 133, Folder 2088)
    Fertility Decline and Recent Changes in Russia: On the Threshold of the Second Demographic Transition, by Elena I. Ivanova and Sergei V. Zakharov. The paper was presented at a conference sponsored by RAND's Center for Russian and Eurasian Studies and the Center of Demography and Human Ecology, Institute for Economic Forecasting, of the Russian Academy of Sciences, June 5-6, 1995. It is not known if or how this paper relates to JCSSS programs.